Will Schiller

Driven individual with over three years experience in digital marketing. Including working for a FTSE 250 company to deliver company-wide SEO strategy while at Moneysupermarket.com group and working within the blockchain startup scene for over a year. A do-er and a get it done kind of person, fast learner and a self-starter.

- Writing and developing company communications
- Blogging for TravelSupermarket
- +3 years commercial SEO experience
- Defining growth strategy

- HTML/CSS/Ruby/JS/Git/Meteor/Angula
- Agile trained
- Strong reporting and analysis skills
- Photoshop CS6 Level 1
- Strong networking and interpersonal skills

Employment History

Ftopia | Marketing - March 2016 to present

I've been working on the Free Ftopia project since it's inception working directly with the CEO who was previously the Backfeed head of international operations growing the team from 3 people to 39 in four months. My main responsibilities are community growth, marketing and SEO.

Backfeed.cc | Work Experience - October 2015 to January 2016

I arranged to do work experience with Backfeed on a remote basis learning about working remotely, attending the Devcon1 Ethereum conference and learning about consensus protocols for blockchain applications. I had accepted to intern with Backfeed but they failed to achieve funding, and the team halved in size and had to cancel my internship.

Other projects - 2015 to present

<u>Redecetralized Conference</u> - Key organiser at London technology conference. <u>Cooperativa Integral Catalana</u> - Studied the P2P communities in Barcelona. <u>bithouse.io</u> - Creator of BitHouse an open source project for registering property on a blockchain.

Sabbatical – 2014 to 2015

TravelSupermarket | **Search Executive** - October 2012 to May 2014

Responsibilities included:

- Content auditing, briefing content writers, working on creative campaigns, PR, above the line and content strategy.
- On-site, off-site SEO, reporting and traffic and revenue analysis.
- Researching and writing publicly on the company blog and Wordpress development.
- Web design.
- Data analysis.
- Conversion rate optimisation.

ThinkMoney | **SEO Developer** - September 2010 to May 2011

As part of a two-person SEO team, I helped deliver SEO strategy, and the site was awarded second best SEO site in Manchester by The Eword SEO agency. Main responsibilities were:

- Link building and managing relationships with around 3000 web-masters.
- Sub-editing and creating content strategy.
- Managing content teams.

Education and qualifications

The University of New Mexico

Web Application Architectures June 2015 • (<u>Coursera MOOC</u>) Distinction – 97.5%

Chester University

Commercial Music Technology September 2007 – July 2009

Sir John Deane's College

A-levels results (including English Literature and French) September 2004 – June 2006

North Cestrian Grammar School

G.C.S.E. results (including English, Maths, Science, business and French)
September 1999 to July 2004

• 3xD grade

FdSc

• 1xE grade

• IT Key Skills Level 2

• 6xA grade

• 2xB grade

• 1xC grade

Phone: +393476 831 431

Email: will.sch@protonmail.com